Register of the National Republic records, 1918-1960
Hoover Institution Archives
- Information File A (Boxes 1-398)
  - Moss, Col. James A.
  - Movies
    - General
    - Clippings
  - Movies (Box 220)
  - Mo, miscellaneous
  - Murphy, Frank
  - Muscle Shoals
  - Murrow, Edward R.
  - Mu, miscellaneous
  - Miscellaneous pamphlets
  - Moral Re-armament [4 folders] (Box 221)
  - Narcotics (Box 222)
  - Nation, The
  - Nation Association, Inc.
  - National Advisory Committee on Illiteracy
  - National Advisory Council on Radio in Education
  - National Americanism Foundation
  - National Anthem
  - National Association of Manufacturers
  - National Bureau of Economic Research
  - National Christian Family Defense League
  - National Citizens Commission for the Public Schools
  - National Citizens Committee
  - National Citizens Committee for Winfred Lynn
  - National Citizens Action Committee
  - National Civic Federation
  - National Civil Liberties Clearing House
  - National Committee for Mental Hygiene
  - National Committee for Fair Minimum Wage
  - National Committee for an Effective Congress
  - National Committee for India's Freedom (Box 223)
  - National Commission for the Defense of Democracy Through Education
  - National Committee for the Defense of Political Prisoners
  - National Committee to Abolish the Poll Tax
  - National Committee to Aid Striking Miners and National Committee Fighting Starvation (same folder)
  - National Committee to Combat Anti-Semitism
  - National Committee to Defeat the Mundt Bill
  - National Committee to Uphold Constitutional Government
  - National Committee on Calendar Simplification
  - National Conference of Jews and Christians [2 folders]
  - National Conference of Christian Ministers and Laymen
  - National Congress of Parents and Teachers
  - National Council Against Conscription
  - National Council for American Education (Box 224)
  - National Council for Protection of Foreign Born
  - National Council on Freedom from Censorship
  - National Defense League
  - National Economic Council Inc.
  - National Economic League (National Economy League)
  - National Economic and Social Planning Association
  - National Education Alliance Inc.
  - National Education Association
  - National Education Association (Box 225)
  - National Emergency Committee (Military Training Camps Association)
  - National Emergency Conference
  - National Emergency Conference for Democratic Rights
  - National Federation for Constitutional Liberties
  - National Federation of Federal Employees
  - National Federation of Religious Liberals
  - National Groups
  - National Guard (Box 226)
    - General
    - Literature
  - National Labor Relations Board
    - General
    - Clippings
    - Saposs, David J.
    - Literature
  - Nationalism
  - National Institute of Social Relations (Box 227)
  - National Issues Committee
  - National Lawyers Guild
  - National Legion
  - National Miners Union
  - National Order of Protestant Clubs
  - National Patriotic League
  - National Patrick Henry Organization
  - National Planning Association
  - National Popular Government League
  - National Preaching Mission (Box 228)
  - National Precinct Workers, Inc.
  - National Progressive League
  - National Republic
    - General
    - Literature [2 folders]
  - National Rifle Association
  - National Sacramento Appeal Committee
  - National Save Our Schools Committee
  - National Small Businessmen's Association
  - National Society of Economic Education and National Economic Education Campaign [same folder]
  - National Sharecroppers Fund, Inc.
  - National Republic Essay Contest
  - National Sojourners (Box 229)
    - General
    - Radio Lectures
  - National, miscellaneous pamphlets
  - National Tax Equality Association
  - National Unemployment League
  - Nationalists
  - Nature Friends, The
  - Navy League
    - General
    - Literature
  - N, miscellaneous
  - Navy
  - Naval Treaty and Conference (Box 230)
  - Naval Treaty
  - National organizations
    - Files of the Committee on Un-American Activities of the U.S. House of Representatives
    - General [5 folders] (Box 231)
  - Nearing, Scott
  - Neutrality [2 folders]
  - New America (Box 232)
  - New Commonwealth Literature
  - Newfoundland
  - New History
  - New Humanist, The
  - National Defense
    - General
    - Articles
    - Clippings (Box 233)
    - Legislation
    - Literature
    - Literature [2 folders] (Box 234)
    - H.R. 1776 (Box 235)
    - New Deal. (See also Office of Civilian Defense)
    - Office of Civilian Defense (OCD) (Box 236)
    - National Defense Advisory Commission and Council of National Defense
  - Nazism
    - General
    - Dies Committee expose
    - Agents
    - German-American Bund
      - General
      - Metcalf expose (Box 237)
    - Nazism in the USA
      - General
        - General
        - Clippings
      - Espionage-sabotage activities. See also German-American Bund and German-American Vocational League
    - German-American Bund leaders
      - General
      - Bahr, Herbert
      - Colespaugh, William and Gimpel, Erich
      - Cramer, Anthony
      - Duquesne, Frederick J. (Box 238)
      - Gross, Dr. Hans
      - Dineen-Behrens-Thomas-Hoffman, et. al.
      - Haupt, Herbert
      - Heine, Edmund
      - Kodel, Simon and Marie
      - Lehmitz, Ernest and Despretter, Erwin
      - Leiner, Helmut and Ketrtnas, Ferdinand
      - Krepper, Carl
      - Ludwig, Kurt and Boehmler, Lucy
      - Molzahn, Kurt; Kunze, Gerhard; Willumeit, Otto A.
      - Silva-Purvis, John
      - Stephan, Max
      - Vallecila, Robert
    - Von Rautter, Wilhelm
    - German-American Vocational League
    - Nazi prisoners of war
    - Nazi propaganda
      - General
      - Viereck trial
      - Trans-Ocean News Service
    - Nazi-Japaneses fifth column activities and Nazism in South and Central America German-American League for Culture
    - Nazi camps in U.S. (Box 239)
    - Espionage-sabotage activities, South and Central America
    - German-American Bund
    - Kuhn, Fritz
    - Chicago Times expose
    - Literature
  - Negroes (Box 240)
    - Communism
    - Demonstrations
    - Criminal
    - Riots
    - Racial problems and disturbances
    - Hastie, William H.
    - Hughes, Langston
    - Pickens, William
    - Powell, A. Clayton
    - Randolph A. Philip
    - Jim Crowism (Box 241)
    - Houston, Charles H.
    - Robeson, Paul
    - Vote, poll tax
    - Organizations
    - NAACP
    - Angelo Herndon Case
    - League of Struggle for Negro Rights (Box 242)
    - National Negro Congress
    - National Urban League
    - Southern Negro Youth Congress
    - Literature [3 folders] (Box 243)
  - New Century Publishers (Box 244)
  - New Education Fellowship
  - New Leader
  - New Masses
  - New Pioneer
  - New Republic
  - New Theater League and School
  - New York Conference for Inalienable Rights
  - New York Evening Post (Box 245)
  - New York State Economic Council, Inc.
  - New Zealand
  - Newspapers
  - Nicaragua
  - Non-Partisan Association for Franchise Education, Inc.
  - New Deal
    - Personnel
      - Miscellaneous
      - Educators (Box 246)
      - Radicals
      - Radicals in government
      - Clippings
      - Aliens (Box 247)
      - Brain Trust
      - Women
      - Rhodes Scholars
      - Bovington, John
      - Braden, Spruille
      - Clayton, Will
      - Watson, Goodwin
      - Dodd, William and Lovett, Robert [Same folder]
      - Arnold, Thurman
      - Berle, Adolph A. Jr.
      - Biddle, Francis
      - Bullitt, William C.
      - Cohen, Benjamin V. (Box 248)
      - Corcoran, Thomas
      - Cromwell, James H. R.
      - Ezekiel, Mordecai
      - Farley, James A.
      - Flynn, Edward J.
      - Frank, Jerome N.
      - Hull, Cordell
      - Henderson, Leon
      - Hiss, Alger
      - Hopkins, Harry L.
      - Ickes, Harold L. - Clippings
      - Jackson, Gardner
      - Jackson, Robert H.
      - Johnson, Hugh S.
      - Jones, Jesse (Commerce Department) (Box 249)
      - Knox, Frank
      - Lasser, David
      - Lattimore, Owen
      - LaVarre, William
      - Leiserson, William M.
      - MacLeish, Archibald
      - Morgenthau, Henry, Jr.
      - Nelson, Donald
      - Niles, David K.
      - Perkins, Miss (Secretary of Labor)
      - Porter, Paul
      - Richberg, Donald
      - Rosenman, Samuel
      - Service, John S.
      - Sifton, Paul
      - Studebaker, John W. (Box 250)
      - Truman, Harry
      - Tugwell, Rexford G.
      - Vincent, John Carter
      - Vincent, Merle D.
      - Welles, Sumner
      - Winant, John G.
    - Dies Committee Expose
    - AAA (Agricultural Adjustment Administration)
    - Board of Economic Warfare
    - Department of Interior
    - Farm Security Administration
    - Federal Communications Commission
    - Federal Housing Administration
    - Federal Power Commission
    - NRA (National Recovery Administration)
    - Navy Department
    - Office of Civilian Defense
    - Office of Economic Warfare
    - Office of Facts and Figures
    - Office of Production Management
    - OPA (Office of Price Administration)
    - OSS (Office of Strategic Services)
    - Securities Exchange Commission (Box 251)
    - War Department
    - War Labor Board
    - Paul McNutt (War Manpower Commission)
    - War Production Board
    - War Relocation Authority
    - Rural Electrification Administration
      - 1933-1934
      - 1935
      - 1936
      - 1937
      - 1938
      - 1939-1940
    - Articles
    - Projects (Box 252)
    - Bureau
      - General
      - National Resources Planning Board
    - State Department [2 folders]
    - AAA (Agriculture Adjustment Administration) (Box 253)
    - HOLC (Home Owners' Loan Corporation)
    - OWI (Office of War Information)
    - RRA (Rural Resettlement Administration)
    - TVA (Tennessee Valley Authority)
    - WPA (Works Progress Administration)
    - WPA Federal Theater Project
    - WPA Expose (Box 254)
    - WPA, Dies Committee Expose
    - WPA, Radicalism in WPA
    - WPA, Clippings [2 folders]
    - WPA, literature (Box 255)
    - WPA, literature (Box 256)
    - FERA, Federal Emergency Relief Administration
    - OPA, Office of Price Administration
    - PWA, Public Works Administration
    - SEC, Securities Exchange Commission
    - National Youth Administration
    - National Youth Administration (Box 257)
    - Opposition
    - Radical Tendencies
    - Propaganda (Box 258)
    - Red Support
    - Reds in Government (Including Republican Reports [2 folders])
    - Opposition, Hearst editorials
    - Legislation
    - Legislation (Box 259)
    - Black Committee
    - Expenditures
    - Farm Program
    - Literature
    - Literature [2 folders] (Box 260)
    - Literature (Box 261)
    - FERA
  - Non-Partisan League
  - Norman, Montagu
  - Norris, George (Sen.)
  - NATO
  - Norway, Vidkun Quisling
  - Novy Mir
  - N, miscellaneous (Box 262)
  - Ne, miscellaneous
  - Nudism
  - Nu, miscellaneous
  - Operation America, Inc.
  - Oaths
  - Obscene literature
  - O'Connell, Jerry L. (Box 263)
  - Oil industry
  - Old age relief
  - Open Forum
  - Open Road
  - O, miscellaneous
  - Ol, miscellaneous
  - Panama (Box 264)
  - Page, Kirby
  - Paraguay
  - PTA
  - Parker, Judge John J.
  - Paternalism
  - Patriot, The
  - Patriotic Societies
  - Patriot Guard of America, The
  - Patriotism
  - Paul Revere
  - P, miscellaneous (Box 265)
  - Peace, Proposals
  - Pearson, and Allen
  - Pease, Frank
  - People's Legislative Service
  - People's Lobby (Box 266)
    - General
    - Clippings
  - People's Mandate
  - People's Party
  - People's Party -- Action for Human Welfare
  - Pepper, Claude, Senator
  - Pershing, John J., General
  - Peru
  - Phelps, William Lyon
  - Philippines
  - Pe, miscellaneous
  - Pacifism (Box 267)
    - General
    - Pamphlets
    - Conferences
    - Pacifists
    - Churches (Box 268)
    - Barbusse, Henri
    - Conferences -- Scientific and Cultural Conferences for World Peace
    - Anti-pacifists
    - Legislation
    - Peace councils
    - Pacifist organizations
      - American Peace Movement
      - General
        - A-B
        - C-F
        - G-J
        - K-P
        - Q-Z (Box 269)
        - General
          - General
          - Large groups
      - Committee for Peaceful Alternative
      - American Peace Society
      - American Peace Mobilization
      - American Union for Concerted Peace Efforts and Committee for Concerted Peace Efforts
      - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace (Box 270)
        - Pamphlets
        - General
        - General (Box 271)
      - Cause and Cure of War
        - General
        - Pamphlets
      - Citizens Keep America Out of War Committee (Box 272)
      - Commission to Study Organization of Peace
        - General
        - Literature
      - Emergency Peace Campaign
        - General
        - Literature
      - Emergency Peace Mobilization (Box 273)
      - Keep America Out of War Committee
      - Keep America Out of War Congress
      - National Committee to Keep America Out of Foreign Wars
      - National Keep America Out of War Committee
      - National Council for Prevention of War
        - Letterheads, clippings
        - Literature
        - Literature (Box 274)
        - General
        - Releases
      - National Committee to Win the Peace (Box 275)
        - General
        - Clippings
      - National Peace Conference
      - New York Peace Association
      - No Foreign War Committee
      - Peace Now Movement
      - Peace Patriots
      - Peacemakers, The
      - Pennsylvania Committee for Total Disarmament
      - Practical Pacifist Club
      - Public Action Committee
      - Southern California Committee for the Peace Plan
      - World Peace Association
      - War Resisters League
      - War Resisters League (Box 276)
      - Washington Peace Mobilization
      - Women
        - General
        - Women's International League for Peace and Freedom
        - General
        - Clippings (Box 277)
        - Literature
      - Women's Peace Union
      - World Peace Foundation
      - World Peace Posters, Inc.
      - World Peaceways, Inc.
      - Youth
  - Pacifist propagand
  - Physicians Forum (Box 278)
  - Pike, Sumner
  - Pilnyak, Boris
  - Pinchot, Gifford
  - Pi, miscellaneous
  - PM
  - Poland (Box 279)
  - Polish American Congress
  - Political and Economic Planning
  - Politics
  - Popular Front (Peoples Front)
  - Population
  - Portugal
  - Post War Planning (Box 280)
  - Pound, Roscoe
  - Power Conference, Third World
  - Pl, miscellaneous
  - Preparedness
  - Presidents, U.S.
  - Press
  - Prisoners of war (Box 281)
  - Prisons
  - Producers' News
  - Production
  - Program Information and Exchange, Inc.
  - Progressives
  - Progressives, Order of White Star
  - Progressive Party, Wallace
  - Progressive Citizens of America [2 folders]
  - Prohibition (Box 282)
  - Proletarian Party
  - Propaganda
  - Proportional representation
  - Protestant, The (Digest)
  - Pr, miscellaneous (Box 283)
  - Public ownership
  - Public Ownership League [2 folders]
  - Public Affairs Institute
  - Public utilities
  - Public Affairs Committee, Inc.
  - Public Affairs Committee, Inc. (Box 284)
  - Publications
  - Puerto Rico
  - Puerto Rico (Box 285)
  - Pu, miscellaneous
  - Q, miscellaneous
  - Radical organizations (Charts)
  - Radio
  - Radio In Education, Inc.
  - Railroads
  - Rand Book Store
  - Rankin, Jeannette
  - Raushenbush, H. Stephen
  - R, miscellaneous (Box 286)
  - Readers' Digest
  - Recht, Charles
  - Reconciliation Trips
  - R.F.C.
  - Red Network
  - Reed, James A.
  - Reforestation
  - Relief
  - Relief, Reds
  - Religious Education Association
  - Reparations
  - The Reporter (Box 287)
  - Religion [2 folders]
  - Republican National Committee
  - Republican Party
    - General
    - Literature (Box 288)
  - Reserve Officers Training Corps
  - Reserve Officers Training Corps Association
  - Re, miscellaneous (Box 289)
  - Ripley, Robert L.
  - Rivera, Diego
  - Ri, miscellaneous
  - Roerich Museum
  - Ro, miscellaneous
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Box 290)
    - Fourth term possiblity
    - Governor
    - Roosevelt policies
    - Roosevelt family
    - Roosevelt, Presidential Campaign, 1932
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor (My Day)
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor [2 folders] (Box 291)
    - New Deal speeches
    - President (Box 292)
    - Third term speeches
  - Robinson-Rubens Case (Box 293)
  - Root, Elihu
  - Rosicrucian Order
  - Rog, miscellaneous
  - Rubber
  - Rumania
  - Russell, George Edward
  - Russian National Revolutionary Fascist Party
  - Russian Revolution
  - Russian War Relief, Inc.
  - Ru, miscellaneous (Box 294)
  - Sabotage and Incendiarism
  - Sabotage and Incendiarism, Europe
  - Sabotage, Armed Forces
  - Sabath, Adolph J.
  - Schools (Box 295)
    - Antireligious propaganda
    - Anticommunist fight
    - District of Columbia
      - General
      - Radicalism
    - Radicalism
      - Colleges
      - Schools and colleges
      - General
      - Duncan expose (Box 296)
    - General
    - Radicalism in high schools [2 folders]
    - Radicalism in schools and colleges
      - General
      - Easley expose
    - Red Rider
    - Textbooks (Box 297)
      - General [2 folders]
      - Building America Series
      - Rugg Books
    - Literature
    - Literature, scholastic (Box 298)
    - High schools, miscellaneous [2 folders]
    - Textbooks, Rugg Books
    - Miscellaneous pamphlets [2 folders] (Box 299)
    - Colleges
      - General
      - Antioch College (Box 300)
      - Abraham Lincoln University
      - Amherst College
      - American University
      - Arizona University
      - Asheville Normal and Teachers College
      - Bacone College
      - Ball State College
      - Barnard
      - Bates
      - Bennington College
      - Boston Teachers
      - Boston University
      - Brenau College
      - Brooklyn College
      - Brookwood College
      - Brown University
      - Bryn Mawr College
      - Butler University
      - Bucknell University
      - Capital University
      - Carleton College
      - Carnegie Institute of Technology
      - Catholic University
      - Central College
      - Citadel
      - City College of Detroit
      - City College of New York (Box 301)
      - Colorado State College of Education
      - Colorado State Teachers College
      - Columbia University
        - General
        - Radicalism
        - Releases
      - Commonwealth College
        - General
        - Reports
        - Releases
      - Commonwealth College Fortnightly (Box 302)
      - Cornell
      - Dartmouth
      - DePauw
      - Duke
      - FERA Schools
      - Fordham
      - Friends University
      - Georgetown University
      - Goucher College
      - Harvard
      - Howard University
      - Henry George School
      - Indiana University (Box 303)
      - Highlander Folk School [2 folders]
      - Johns Hopkins University
      - Hunter College
      - Los Angeles Junior College
      - MIT
      - Michigan State
      - Milwaukee State Teachers College
      - Moscow State University (Moscow University Summer Institute)
      - Mount Holyoke (Box 304)
      - New School for Social Research [2 folders]
      - Rand School for Social Science [2 folders]
      - New York University (Box 305)
      - Northwestern
      - Oberlin
      - Ohio State
      - Oxford University
      - Princeton
      - Rutgers
      - Reed
      - Rollins
      - Roosevelt College
      - St. Joseph's College
      - Smith
      - Southern (Summer) School for Workers
      - Stanford
      - Swarthmore
      - Syracuse University (Box 306)
      - Tampa College
      - Teachers College, Columbia [2 folders]
      - Temple University
      - Tulane University
      - Vassar College
      - Vassar College Reports
      - Wesleyan University
      - Wellesley
      - Wheaton
      - Yale
      - Union Theological Seminary
      - University of Akron
      - University of Alabama
      - University of California
      - University of California at Los Angeles
      - University of Cincinnati
      - University of Chicago
      - University of Colorado (Box 307)
      - University of Kansas
      - University of Louisville
      - University of Maryland
      - University of Michigan
      - University of Minnesota
      - University of Missouri
      - University of North Carolina
      - University of Pittsburgh
      - University of Pennsylvania
      - University of Texas
      - University of Virginia
      - University of Virginia Institute of Public Affairs
      - Verde Valley School
      - University of Wichita
      - University of Wisconsin
      - University of Washington
    - Students (Box 308)
      - Radical
      - College
      - Grade School
      - High School
      - National Students Association
      - National Students Federation
      - American Students Union
      - International Students Service
      - Students Organizations [2 folders] (Box 309)
      - International Collegiate Disbarment Council
      - International Student Assembly
      - National Student League
      - American Student Union
      - American Student Union (Box 310)
      - Student Americaneers
      - Pacifist activities
      - Students Patriotic League
      - World Student Congress
  - Sc, miscellaneous (Box 311)
  - Scripps, Howard
  - Sci, miscellaneous
  - Sedition, General
  - Sedition trial (Box 312)
    - General
    - Clippings
    - Dennis, Lawrence (Box 313)
    - Edmondson, Robert E.
    - Garner, Elmer J. and Garner, James
    - Griffin, William
    - McWilliams, Joseph E.
    - Sanctuary, Eugene
    - Smythe, Edward J.
    - Winrod, Gerald B.
  - Se, miscellaneous
  - Sh, miscellaneous
  - Shi, miscellaneous
  - Si, miscellaneous
  - Smi, miscellaneous
  - Schwellenbach, Lewis B.
  - Seldes, George
  - Senatorial Tour, War Fronts, 1943 (Box 314)
  - Sentinels of the Republic
  - Sex study and literature [2 folders]
  - Sharecroppers
  - Shaw, George B.
  - Shirt Movements
  - Shirt Movements (Box 315)
  - Shirt Movements, Silver Shirts
  - Sinclair, Upton
  - Sinclair, Upton (Box 316)
  - Slovak League of America
  - Smith, Alfred E.
  - Smith, Gerald L.K. (America First Party)
  - Smith, Thomas V. (Box 317)
  - Social Action
  - Social Frontier
  - Social Groups
  - Social Insurance
  - Socialist Party Platforms
    - Clippings
    - Literature
    - Pamphlets
    - General
  - Socialization (Box 318)
  - Socialism, Canada
  - Socialism, Foreign Countries
  - Socialist Labor party
  - Socialist - General
  - Socialists, Norman Thomas
  - Socialist Party, Left Wing
  - Socialism
  - Socialist Organizations (Box 319)
  - Socialist Organizations, Young Peoples Socialist League
  - Socialists, Heywood Broun
  - Socialists - Communists
  - Social Democratic Federation
  - Socialists, (Morris Hillquit)
  - Socialists - Louis Waldman
  - Socialist Workers Party
  - Social Problems
  - Social Security Act
  - Society for Ethical Culture (American Ethical Union)
  - Socialized Medicine
    - General
    - Clippings
    - Clippings (Box 320)
    - Literature
  - Society for Prevention of World War III, literature (Box 321)
  - Southern Conference for Human Welfare
  - Southern Conference Educational Funds, Inc.
  - Southern Regional Council (Box 322)
  - Society of Peter the Great
  - Sons of American Revolution
  - Sorenson, Charles E. (Ford Company)
  - South America
  - Soviet-American Securities Corporation
  - Sn, miscellaneous
  - Spargo, John
  - Special Committee to Investigate Un-American Activities (Box 323)
  - Spivak, John L.
  - Sp, miscellaneous
  - Stable Money Association
  - Stage
  - Standard Oil Company
  - Staples, Orville
  - Stassen, Harold E.
  - State Department
  - State Rights
  - Steel, Johannes
  - Stefansson, Vilhjalmur
  - Stern, Julius David (Box 324)
  - Steuben Society of America
  - Stevenson, Adlai